<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2025-04-19T11:43:34+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alembic</title><subtitle>Alembic is a starting point for Jekyll projects. Rather than starting from scratch, this boilerplate is designed to get the ball rolling immediately</subtitle><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><entry><title type="html">A1 Takeaways Hong Kong Style BBQ</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A1 Takeaways Hong Kong Style BBQ" /><published>2024-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ/"><![CDATA[<p>Rating: 2</p>

<p>We ate dinner here in November 2024</p>

<p>Shredded duck with plum sauce on rice<br />
Tofu with vegetables and spicy sauce on rice</p>

<p>A1 Takeaways, despite the name, does do dine-in. It’s only 4 tables, but you’ll probably be fine without a reservation. We were impressed that, compared to recent experiences, A1 asked us if we were dining in and, when we said yes, served us on a plate rather than in a takeaway container. Was the plate paper and the cutlery a wooden fork? Sure. But some effort was made. We also enjoyed when a squad of four lads came in later who were clearly friendly with the owner. They were having a good yarn and organising dates for something. It gave a sense that A1 is a real part of the community. Points for super speedy service, and for value for money too. (especially the tofu - $13.50 for a full sized meal!)</p>

<p>We regret that we’re unable to gush so emphatically about the food itself. The duck was of pretty good quality, nice skin, but came chopped rather than shredded as advertised. The plum sauce was extremely sweet, pale, and not recognisable as plum. The tofu had an unpleasant fryer taste and the ‘spicy’ sauce was more sweet than spicy.</p>

<p>A1 Takeaways Hong Kong Style BBQ has no website.</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rating: 2 We ate dinner here in November 2024 Shredded duck with plum sauce on rice Tofu with vegetables and spicy sauce on rice A1 Takeaways, despite the name, does do dine-in. It’s only 4 tables, but you’ll probably be fine without a reservation. We were impressed that, compared to recent experiences, A1 asked us if we were dining in and, when we said yes, served us on a plate rather than in a takeaway container. Was the plate paper and the cutlery a wooden fork? Sure. But some effort was made. We also enjoyed when a squad of four lads came in later who were clearly friendly with the owner. They were having a good yarn and organising dates for something. It gave a sense that A1 is a real part of the community. Points for super speedy service, and for value for money too. (especially the tofu - $13.50 for a full sized meal!) We regret that we’re unable to gush so emphatically about the food itself. The duck was of pretty good quality, nice skin, but came chopped rather than shredded as advertised. The plum sauce was extremely sweet, pale, and not recognisable as plum. The tofu had an unpleasant fryer taste and the ‘spicy’ sauce was more sweet than spicy. A1 Takeaways Hong Kong Style BBQ has no website.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rusty Bros</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rusty Bros" /><published>2024-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros/"><![CDATA[<p>Rating: 2</p>

<p>We ate lunch here in November 2024</p>

<p>Strawberry milkshake<br />
Jackfruit sliders<br />
Polenta chips<br />
Garlic bread</p>

<p>Let us tell you what we don’t appreciate. Lies. Restaurants who claim a quality or nature of ingredients that makes them sound fancy, tricks you into ordering, then doesn’t deliver. How would you like to try a strawberry milkshake made with strawberry ganache? Sounds pretty good doesn’t it? So you could colour us disappointed when we saw with our own eyes the waiter pumping some kind of bottled syrup into our milkshake. Also, lies on lies, where was the coleslaw and aioli in the sliders? Hanging out with the strawberry ganache in imaginary-land probably!</p>

<p>The highlight of the meal was the garlic bread. It was hot and fresh with plenty of garlic butter and a lovely roasty garlic flavour. But enough of the compliments, let’s talk about the polenta chips. Perhaps they had been fried too long, perhaps they were just cheap old frozen polenta chips, but either way they were dry as a fortnight of Sundays and while you could see the rosemary, you certainly couldn’t taste it.</p>

<p>Website https://therustybros.nz/</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rating: 2 We ate lunch here in November 2024 Strawberry milkshake Jackfruit sliders Polenta chips Garlic bread Let us tell you what we don’t appreciate. Lies. Restaurants who claim a quality or nature of ingredients that makes them sound fancy, tricks you into ordering, then doesn’t deliver. How would you like to try a strawberry milkshake made with strawberry ganache? Sounds pretty good doesn’t it? So you could colour us disappointed when we saw with our own eyes the waiter pumping some kind of bottled syrup into our milkshake. Also, lies on lies, where was the coleslaw and aioli in the sliders? Hanging out with the strawberry ganache in imaginary-land probably! The highlight of the meal was the garlic bread. It was hot and fresh with plenty of garlic butter and a lovely roasty garlic flavour. But enough of the compliments, let’s talk about the polenta chips. Perhaps they had been fried too long, perhaps they were just cheap old frozen polenta chips, but either way they were dry as a fortnight of Sundays and while you could see the rosemary, you certainly couldn’t taste it. Website https://therustybros.nz/]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Urban Gusto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Urban Gusto" /><published>2024-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto/"><![CDATA[<p>Rating: 3</p>

<p>We ate dinner here in November 2024</p>

<p>Pear, gongonzola, rocket and pine nut pizza<br />
Roasted cauliflower with parmesan and cherry tomatoes<br />
Biscoff tiramisu<br />
White chocolate blueberry arancini</p>

<p>Something very unusual happened at Urban Gusto this evening. We were asked for genuine feedback. We’re not talking about the perfunctory “how was your meal” either. When dropping off the tiramisu, the waiter said “we’ve had this on the specials menu for a couple of weeks, would love your feedback.” We subsequently didn’t see that waiter again, but hopefully he gets to read this review. So here goes - the flavours were yummy, we liked the crumbled up biscoff on the top, but that was not a tiramisu. It had no coffee. Also it was very sweet, especially with the caramel in the bottom so it became cloying after a while. Also, the glass you served it in was too tall. We recommend you try soaking the biscoff in coffee, the way you would for ladyfingers in a traditional tiramisu.</p>

<p>That’s an unfortunate way to start this review, as actually we really liked eating here. The pizza was extremely good. Thin, crispy base. Cheesy but not too much. All the flavours worked really well together. And the rocket was carefully distributed and of an appropriate amount. We’d eat that again any day of the week. We were excited to see the dessert arancini, which was a first for us. The balls contained rice, like a fried rice pudding, with plenty of cinnamon, tonnes of blueberries, the right amount of white chocolate, the whole thing was top tier.</p>

<p>The cauliflower was very controversial. The Fee-Rex found it bland, didn’t appreciate the cherry tomatoes, and was looking around on the table like is there some salt here I can apply. Business Andy thought it was marvellous. He could really taste the parmesan and thought the cherry tomatoes were a perfect accompaniment. We could at least both agree that the crispy roast bits on the edges were very pleasant.</p>

<p>Website https://urbangusto.co.nz/</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rating: 3 We ate dinner here in November 2024 Pear, gongonzola, rocket and pine nut pizza Roasted cauliflower with parmesan and cherry tomatoes Biscoff tiramisu White chocolate blueberry arancini Something very unusual happened at Urban Gusto this evening. We were asked for genuine feedback. We’re not talking about the perfunctory “how was your meal” either. When dropping off the tiramisu, the waiter said “we’ve had this on the specials menu for a couple of weeks, would love your feedback.” We subsequently didn’t see that waiter again, but hopefully he gets to read this review. So here goes - the flavours were yummy, we liked the crumbled up biscoff on the top, but that was not a tiramisu. It had no coffee. Also it was very sweet, especially with the caramel in the bottom so it became cloying after a while. Also, the glass you served it in was too tall. We recommend you try soaking the biscoff in coffee, the way you would for ladyfingers in a traditional tiramisu. That’s an unfortunate way to start this review, as actually we really liked eating here. The pizza was extremely good. Thin, crispy base. Cheesy but not too much. All the flavours worked really well together. And the rocket was carefully distributed and of an appropriate amount. We’d eat that again any day of the week. We were excited to see the dessert arancini, which was a first for us. The balls contained rice, like a fried rice pudding, with plenty of cinnamon, tonnes of blueberries, the right amount of white chocolate, the whole thing was top tier. The cauliflower was very controversial. The Fee-Rex found it bland, didn’t appreciate the cherry tomatoes, and was looking around on the table like is there some salt here I can apply. Business Andy thought it was marvellous. He could really taste the parmesan and thought the cherry tomatoes were a perfect accompaniment. We could at least both agree that the crispy roast bits on the edges were very pleasant. Website https://urbangusto.co.nz/]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stratosfare Restaurant &amp;amp; Bar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/02/22/Stratosfare-Restaurant-&-Bar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stratosfare Restaurant &amp;amp; Bar" /><published>2024-02-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/02/22/Stratosfare-Restaurant-&amp;-Bar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/02/22/Stratosfare-Restaurant-&amp;-Bar/"><![CDATA[<p>Rating: 1</p>

<p>We ate lunch here in November 2024</p>

<p>Buffet</p>

<p>A buffet is such a rare dining experience for us that when we realise we’re heading into a buffet, for a second we get a bit excited. Then the irrefutable truth of the buffet dawns on us and we remember that, while good buffets do exist, they are extremely rare.</p>

<p>Stratosfare thinks quite highly of itself, but doesn’t have the chops (or other meats) to back it up. We will say they are correct about the view, it’s pretty nice. And we appreciated the bustling hive of activity up on the hill, between the mountain bike competition, the gondolas, the luge, the freshly sheared alpacas, there was plenty to see.</p>

<p>Stratosfare is a bar, as well as a restaurant, and they have a good looking cocktail menu. Unfortunately, the cocktails themselves were downright awful. We got a salted caramel espresso martini and a black forest mudslide. Yum yum, right? Wrong. After taking an extremely long time to arrive, the black forest had a nasty liquer taste while the martini was watery and not sweet, and didn’t have that delicious coffee flavour either. We often scarf down cocktails at lightning speed; these two were both left at the end of the meal and it was hard going to finish them.</p>

<p>Nothing from the buffet was really worth eating. The raspberry jelly was alright. The brownie was alright, but we don’t believe any of the slices, or the hard bready little donuts, were made on site. The roast potatoes were acceptable but lacked crispness. The bread rolls were squished and firm. The 24-hour slow roast beef with homemade gravy was a great disappointment. The guy was carving it right there, he could work around the gristle if he wanted. But he didn’t want to, and the Fee-Rex literally had to spit a piece out when she found out it was 80% hyper-chewy gristle. The gravy was foul. It had a very strong flavour like somebody had put in a whole tub of Marmite. Hell, maybe even a whole tub of Vegemite.</p>

<p>The desserts were the best of a bad bunch. The pavlova was okay with a nice mix of fruit on top. They offered six different ice cream flavours, which we appreciated, but it was all very airy, non-creamy, the cheapest of the cheap. The mousse had a bitter cocoa flavour. We definitely regretted the amount of dessert we took, so if you are going to come to Stratosfare (which you shouldn’t), approach with caution.</p>

<p>Website https://rotorua.skyline.co.nz/things-to-do/stratosfare-restaurant-rotorua/?utm_source=gmb_listing&amp;utm_medium=organic</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rating: 1 We ate lunch here in November 2024 Buffet A buffet is such a rare dining experience for us that when we realise we’re heading into a buffet, for a second we get a bit excited. Then the irrefutable truth of the buffet dawns on us and we remember that, while good buffets do exist, they are extremely rare. Stratosfare thinks quite highly of itself, but doesn’t have the chops (or other meats) to back it up. We will say they are correct about the view, it’s pretty nice. And we appreciated the bustling hive of activity up on the hill, between the mountain bike competition, the gondolas, the luge, the freshly sheared alpacas, there was plenty to see. Stratosfare is a bar, as well as a restaurant, and they have a good looking cocktail menu. Unfortunately, the cocktails themselves were downright awful. We got a salted caramel espresso martini and a black forest mudslide. Yum yum, right? Wrong. After taking an extremely long time to arrive, the black forest had a nasty liquer taste while the martini was watery and not sweet, and didn’t have that delicious coffee flavour either. We often scarf down cocktails at lightning speed; these two were both left at the end of the meal and it was hard going to finish them. Nothing from the buffet was really worth eating. The raspberry jelly was alright. The brownie was alright, but we don’t believe any of the slices, or the hard bready little donuts, were made on site. The roast potatoes were acceptable but lacked crispness. The bread rolls were squished and firm. The 24-hour slow roast beef with homemade gravy was a great disappointment. The guy was carving it right there, he could work around the gristle if he wanted. But he didn’t want to, and the Fee-Rex literally had to spit a piece out when she found out it was 80% hyper-chewy gristle. The gravy was foul. It had a very strong flavour like somebody had put in a whole tub of Marmite. Hell, maybe even a whole tub of Vegemite. The desserts were the best of a bad bunch. The pavlova was okay with a nice mix of fruit on top. They offered six different ice cream flavours, which we appreciated, but it was all very airy, non-creamy, the cheapest of the cheap. The mousse had a bitter cocoa flavour. We definitely regretted the amount of dessert we took, so if you are going to come to Stratosfare (which you shouldn’t), approach with caution. Website https://rotorua.skyline.co.nz/things-to-do/stratosfare-restaurant-rotorua/?utm_source=gmb_listing&amp;utm_medium=organic]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Madly Indian</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/Madly-Indian/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Madly Indian" /><published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/Madly-Indian</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/Madly-Indian/"><![CDATA[<p>Rating: 3</p>

<p>We ate dinner here in November 2023</p>

<p>Lamb do pyaza<br />
Paneer chettinaud<br />
Butter naan<br />
Cheese naan</p>

<p>While it can be hard to stand out when you’re an Indian restaurant, doing the basics right can take you a long way. So while they didn’t quite take us to the moon and back, truly Madly deeply Indian certainly didn’t crash and burn.</p>

<p>The best thing was probably the chettinaud sauce, and the worst was  the cheese naan, in which none of the promised cheddar appeared. That was Edam at best. We don’t know why Business Andy keeps ordering cheese naans, they just end up breaking his heart every time.  Special shout out to Madly Indian’s rice, they’d added some extra spices which really elevated it.</p>

<p>Website https://madlyindian.co.nz/</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rating: 3 We ate dinner here in November 2023 Lamb do pyaza Paneer chettinaud Butter naan Cheese naan While it can be hard to stand out when you’re an Indian restaurant, doing the basics right can take you a long way. So while they didn’t quite take us to the moon and back, truly Madly deeply Indian certainly didn’t crash and burn. The best thing was probably the chettinaud sauce, and the worst was the cheese naan, in which none of the promised cheddar appeared. That was Edam at best. We don’t know why Business Andy keeps ordering cheese naans, they just end up breaking his heart every time. Special shout out to Madly Indian’s rice, they’d added some extra spices which really elevated it. Website https://madlyindian.co.nz/]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Zane Grey’s Restaurant &amp;amp; Bar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/Zane-Grey's-Restaurant-&-Bar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zane Grey’s Restaurant &amp;amp; Bar" /><published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/Zane-Grey&apos;s-Restaurant-&amp;-Bar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/Zane-Grey&apos;s-Restaurant-&amp;-Bar/"><![CDATA[<p>Rating: 1</p>

<p>We ate dinner here in November 2023</p>

<p>Fish chips and salad<br />
Cheese burger with chips</p>

<p>Screw you Zane. We’ve been to places like this before, tourist traps with a great location who then don’t need to try because they know people will come in thanks to the location, and with most just passing through return business is no concern.</p>

<p>Fair play, it is a beautiful spot with plenty of seating on a large deck jutting out into the water, the kind of place you can watch the birds and hope to see a dolphin.</p>

<p>That’s where the compliments end. Here are their food crimes in no particular order</p>
<ul>
  <li>Overpriced</li>
  <li>The worlds tiniest sliver of lemon to squeeze on the fish. You couldn’t even squeeze it, it just crumpled into dust, that’s how thin it was. It was less than enough lemon for a gin and tonic</li>
  <li>Menu said aioli then the chips came with tomato sauce instead. Stop it you lazy fucks.</li>
  <li>Totally gutless tartare sauce. It was so gutless it might have actually just been bland aioli, but it came with the fish we figured it was meant to be tartare.</li>
  <li>Bad chips. We had difficulty pinpointing what exactly made them bad, they were not cold or soggy or anything obvious, they just didn’t taste good and were a labour to get through</li>
  <li>Terrible distribution of bacon in the burger. It was literally all in one corner, meaning that Business Andy never even knew there was bacon in the burger at all as his half contained zero bacon.</li>
</ul>

<p>We won’t stand for it, Zane.</p>

<p>Website https://www.zanegreys.co.nz/</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rating: 1 We ate dinner here in November 2023 Fish chips and salad Cheese burger with chips Screw you Zane. We’ve been to places like this before, tourist traps with a great location who then don’t need to try because they know people will come in thanks to the location, and with most just passing through return business is no concern. Fair play, it is a beautiful spot with plenty of seating on a large deck jutting out into the water, the kind of place you can watch the birds and hope to see a dolphin. That’s where the compliments end. Here are their food crimes in no particular order Overpriced The worlds tiniest sliver of lemon to squeeze on the fish. You couldn’t even squeeze it, it just crumpled into dust, that’s how thin it was. It was less than enough lemon for a gin and tonic Menu said aioli then the chips came with tomato sauce instead. Stop it you lazy fucks. Totally gutless tartare sauce. It was so gutless it might have actually just been bland aioli, but it came with the fish we figured it was meant to be tartare. Bad chips. We had difficulty pinpointing what exactly made them bad, they were not cold or soggy or anything obvious, they just didn’t taste good and were a labour to get through Terrible distribution of bacon in the burger. It was literally all in one corner, meaning that Business Andy never even knew there was bacon in the burger at all as his half contained zero bacon. We won’t stand for it, Zane. Website https://www.zanegreys.co.nz/]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello, World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, World" /><published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2023/12/08/hello-world/"><![CDATA[<p>This is my very first blog post. I haven’t written anything yet but I’m sure I have some great stories to tell.</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is my very first blog post. I haven’t written anything yet but I’m sure I have some great stories to tell.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Description of a Pot Still</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2016/08/29/example-post-three/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Description of a Pot Still" /><published>2016-08-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2016/08/29/example-post-three</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2016/08/29/example-post-three/"><![CDATA[<p>A pot still is a type of still used in distilling spirits such as whisky or brandy. Heat is applied directly to the pot containing the wash (for whisky) or wine (for brandy). This is called a batch distillation (as opposed to a continuous distillation).</p>

<p>At standard atmospheric pressure, alcohol boils at 78 °C (172 °F), while water boils at 100 °C (212 °F). During distillation, the vapour contains more alcohol than the liquid. When the vapours are condensed, the resulting liquid contains a higher concentration of alcohol. In the pot still, the alcohol and water vapour combine with esters and flow from the still through the condensing coil. There they condense into the first distillation liquid, the so-called “low wines”. The low wines have a strength of about 25–35% alcohol by volume, and flow into a second still. It is then distilled a second time to produce the colourless spirit, collected at about 70% alcohol by volume. Colour is added through maturation in an oak aging barrel, and develops over time.</p>

<p>The modern pot still is a descendant of the alembic, an earlier distillation device.</p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A pot still is a type of still used in distilling spirits such as whisky or brandy. Heat is applied directly to the pot containing the wash (for whisky) or wine (for brandy).]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://picsum.photos/2560/600?image=733" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://picsum.photos/2560/600?image=733" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">History of the Alembic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/history/external%20sources/2016/08/28/example-post-two/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History of the Alembic" /><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/history/external%20sources/2016/08/28/example-post-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/history/external%20sources/2016/08/28/example-post-two/"><![CDATA[<p>Dioscorides’ ambix (described in his De materia medica) is a helmet-shaped lid for gathering condensed mercury. For Athenaeus (~ 225 C.E.) it is a bottle or flask. For later chemists it denotes various parts of crude distillation devices.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Alembic drawings appear in works of Cleopatra the Alchemist, Synesius, and Zosimos of Panopolis. There were alembics with two (dibikos) and three (tribikos) receivers.[4] According to Zosimos of Panopolis, the alembic was invented by Mary the Jewess.[5]</p>

<p>The anbik is described by Ibn al-Awwam in his Kitab al-Filaha (Book of Agriculture), where he explains how rose-water is distilled. Amongst others, it is mentioned in the Mafatih al-Ulum (Key of Sciences) of Khwarizmi and the Kitab al-Asrar (Book of Secrets) of Al-Razi. Some illustrations occur in the Latin translations of works which are attributed to Geber.[2]</p>

<p><em>Originally from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alembic">Alembic - Wikipedia</a></em></p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="History" /><category term="External sources" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dioscorides’ ambix (described in his De materia medica) is a helmet-shaped lid for gathering condensed mercury. For Athenaeus (~ 225 C.E.) it is a bottle or flask. For later chemists it denotes various parts of crude distillation devices.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Description of an Alembic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/external%20sources/2016/08/27/example-post-one/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Description of an Alembic" /><published>2016-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/external%20sources/2016/08/27/example-post-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/external%20sources/2016/08/27/example-post-one/"><![CDATA[<p>The complete distilling apparatus consists of three parts: the “cucurbit” (Arabic ḳarʿa, Greek βίκος), the still pot containing the liquid to be distilled, which is heated by a flame; the “head” or “cap” (Arabic anbiḳ, Greek ἄμβιξ) which fits over the mouth of the cucurbit to receive the vapors, with an attached downward-sloping “tube” (Greek σωλήν), leading to the “receiver” (Arabic ḳābila, Greek ἄγγος or φιάλη) container.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Retorts have the “cap” and the “cucurbit” made into one. The anbik is also called the raʾs (head) of the cucurbit. The liquid in the cucurbit is heated or boiled; the vapour rises into the anbik, where it cools by contact with the walls and condenses, running down the spout into the receiver. A modern descendant of the alembic is the pot still, used to produce distilled beverages.</p>

<p><em>Originally from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alembic">Alembic - Wikipedia</a></em></p>]]></content><author><name>DavidDarnes</name></author><category term="General" /><category term="External sources" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The complete distilling apparatus consists of three parts: the “cucurbit” (Arabic ḳarʿa, Greek βίκος), the still pot containing the liquid to be distilled, which is heated by a flame; the “head” or “cap” (Arabic anbiḳ, Greek ἄμβιξ) which fits over the mouth of the cucurbit to receive the vapors, with an attached downward-sloping “tube” (Greek σωλήν), leading to the “receiver” (Arabic ḳābila, Greek ἄγγος or φιάλη) container.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>