<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2025-04-25T11:45:32+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/feed.xml</id><title type="html">BAATFR</title><subtitle>Restaurant reviews</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kaimak</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/04/24/Kaimak/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kaimak" /><published>2025-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/04/24/Kaimak</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/04/24/Kaimak/"><![CDATA[<p>Salami pide<br />
Halloumi iskender</p>

<p>It’s a tough decision for places trying to do well in both takeaway and dine-in; door open or door closed? On one hand, door open helps traffic flow and encourages customers for the takeaway trade, as well as discouraging loitering dine-in clientele (AKA the Burger King technique). On the other hand, it’s pretty bloody cold in autumn for your dine in customers. We ate in our puffer jackets.</p>

<p>Luckily, the food was very good. The pide was flavourful with good sized chunks of salami, it wasn’t greasy like some pide can be, and the ends weren’t just useless nubbins of doughy bread, the topping went all the way to the end. It also came with two fantastic accompaniments - yellow chillis and pickled cabbage. We were skeptical when we saw these. The waiter warned us the chillis were hot, and he was quite correct as the Fee-Rex learned when she tried to eat one straight up. However, when used as intended as a pairing to the pide it was a fantastic addition, as was the cabbage.</p>

<p>The halloumi iskender was also strong. There was plenty of everything and in good ratios. Generous with the hummus too, which is nice to see. Yes there could have been more halloumi, but that’s basically always the case.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Salami pide Halloumi iskender It’s a tough decision for places trying to do well in both takeaway and dine-in; door open or door closed? On one hand, door open helps traffic flow and encourages customers for the takeaway trade, as well as discouraging loitering dine-in clientele (AKA the Burger King technique). On the other hand, it’s pretty bloody cold in autumn for your dine in customers. We ate in our puffer jackets. Luckily, the food was very good. The pide was flavourful with good sized chunks of salami, it wasn’t greasy like some pide can be, and the ends weren’t just useless nubbins of doughy bread, the topping went all the way to the end. It also came with two fantastic accompaniments - yellow chillis and pickled cabbage. We were skeptical when we saw these. The waiter warned us the chillis were hot, and he was quite correct as the Fee-Rex learned when she tried to eat one straight up. However, when used as intended as a pairing to the pide it was a fantastic addition, as was the cabbage. The halloumi iskender was also strong. There was plenty of everything and in good ratios. Generous with the hummus too, which is nice to see. Yes there could have been more halloumi, but that’s basically always the case.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A1 Takeaways Hong Kong Style BBQ</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A1 Takeaways Hong Kong Style BBQ" /><published>2024-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ/"><![CDATA[<p>Shredded duck with plum sauce on rice<br />
Tofu with vegetables and spicy sauce on rice</p>

<p>A1 Takeaways, despite the name, does do dine-in. It’s only 4 tables, but you’ll probably be fine without a reservation. We were impressed that, compared to recent experiences, A1 asked us if we were dining in and, when we said yes, served us on a plate rather than in a takeaway container. Was the plate paper and the cutlery a wooden fork? Sure. But some effort was made. We also enjoyed when a squad of four lads came in later who were clearly friendly with the owner. They were having a good yarn and organising dates for something. It gave a sense that A1 is a real part of the community. Points for super speedy service, and for value for money too. (especially the tofu - $13.50 for a full sized meal!)</p>

<p>We regret that we’re unable to gush so emphatically about the food itself. The duck was of pretty good quality, nice skin, but came chopped rather than shredded as advertised. The plum sauce was extremely sweet, pale, and not recognisable as plum. The tofu had an unpleasant fryer taste and the ‘spicy’ sauce was more sweet than spicy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shredded duck with plum sauce on rice Tofu with vegetables and spicy sauce on rice A1 Takeaways, despite the name, does do dine-in. It’s only 4 tables, but you’ll probably be fine without a reservation. We were impressed that, compared to recent experiences, A1 asked us if we were dining in and, when we said yes, served us on a plate rather than in a takeaway container. Was the plate paper and the cutlery a wooden fork? Sure. But some effort was made. We also enjoyed when a squad of four lads came in later who were clearly friendly with the owner. They were having a good yarn and organising dates for something. It gave a sense that A1 is a real part of the community. Points for super speedy service, and for value for money too. (especially the tofu - $13.50 for a full sized meal!) We regret that we’re unable to gush so emphatically about the food itself. The duck was of pretty good quality, nice skin, but came chopped rather than shredded as advertised. The plum sauce was extremely sweet, pale, and not recognisable as plum. The tofu had an unpleasant fryer taste and the ‘spicy’ sauce was more sweet than spicy.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rusty Bros</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rusty Bros" /><published>2024-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros/"><![CDATA[<p>Strawberry milkshake<br />
Jackfruit sliders<br />
Polenta chips<br />
Garlic bread</p>

<p>Let us tell you what we don’t appreciate. Lies. Restaurants who claim a quality or nature of ingredients that makes them sound fancy, tricks you into ordering, then doesn’t deliver. How would you like to try a strawberry milkshake made with strawberry ganache? Sounds pretty good doesn’t it? So you could colour us disappointed when we saw with our own eyes the waiter pumping some kind of bottled syrup into our milkshake. Also, lies on lies, where was the coleslaw and aioli in the sliders? Hanging out with the strawberry ganache in imaginary-land probably!</p>

<p>The highlight of the meal was the garlic bread. It was hot and fresh with plenty of garlic butter and a lovely roasty garlic flavour. But enough of the compliments, let’s talk about the polenta chips. Perhaps they had been fried too long, perhaps they were just cheap old frozen polenta chips, but either way they were dry as a fortnight of Sundays and while you could see the rosemary, you certainly couldn’t taste it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Strawberry milkshake Jackfruit sliders Polenta chips Garlic bread Let us tell you what we don’t appreciate. Lies. Restaurants who claim a quality or nature of ingredients that makes them sound fancy, tricks you into ordering, then doesn’t deliver. How would you like to try a strawberry milkshake made with strawberry ganache? Sounds pretty good doesn’t it? So you could colour us disappointed when we saw with our own eyes the waiter pumping some kind of bottled syrup into our milkshake. Also, lies on lies, where was the coleslaw and aioli in the sliders? Hanging out with the strawberry ganache in imaginary-land probably! The highlight of the meal was the garlic bread. It was hot and fresh with plenty of garlic butter and a lovely roasty garlic flavour. But enough of the compliments, let’s talk about the polenta chips. Perhaps they had been fried too long, perhaps they were just cheap old frozen polenta chips, but either way they were dry as a fortnight of Sundays and while you could see the rosemary, you certainly couldn’t taste it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Urban Gusto</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Urban Gusto" /><published>2024-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto/"><![CDATA[<p>Pear, gongonzola, rocket and pine nut pizza<br />
Roasted cauliflower with parmesan and cherry tomatoes<br />
Biscoff tiramisu<br />
White chocolate blueberry arancini</p>

<p>Something very unusual happened at Urban Gusto this evening. We were asked for genuine feedback. We’re not talking about the perfunctory “how was your meal” either. When dropping off the tiramisu, the waiter said “we’ve had this on the specials menu for a couple of weeks, would love your feedback.” We subsequently didn’t see that waiter again, but hopefully he gets to read this review. So here goes - the flavours were yummy, we liked the crumbled up biscoff on the top, but that was not a tiramisu. It had no coffee. Also it was very sweet, especially with the caramel in the bottom so it became cloying after a while. Also, the glass you served it in was too tall. We recommend you try soaking the biscoff in coffee, the way you would for ladyfingers in a traditional tiramisu.</p>

<p>That’s an unfortunate way to start this review, as actually we really liked eating here. The pizza was extremely good. Thin, crispy base. Cheesy but not too much. All the flavours worked really well together. And the rocket was carefully distributed and of an appropriate amount. We’d eat that again any day of the week. We were excited to see the dessert arancini, which was a first for us. The balls contained rice, like a fried rice pudding, with plenty of cinnamon, tonnes of blueberries, the right amount of white chocolate, the whole thing was top tier.</p>

<p>The cauliflower was very controversial. The Fee-Rex found it bland, didn’t appreciate the cherry tomatoes, and was looking around on the table like is there some salt here I can apply. Business Andy thought it was marvellous. He could really taste the parmesan and thought the cherry tomatoes were a perfect accompaniment. We could at least both agree that the crispy roast bits on the edges were very pleasant.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pear, gongonzola, rocket and pine nut pizza Roasted cauliflower with parmesan and cherry tomatoes Biscoff tiramisu White chocolate blueberry arancini Something very unusual happened at Urban Gusto this evening. We were asked for genuine feedback. We’re not talking about the perfunctory “how was your meal” either. When dropping off the tiramisu, the waiter said “we’ve had this on the specials menu for a couple of weeks, would love your feedback.” We subsequently didn’t see that waiter again, but hopefully he gets to read this review. So here goes - the flavours were yummy, we liked the crumbled up biscoff on the top, but that was not a tiramisu. It had no coffee. Also it was very sweet, especially with the caramel in the bottom so it became cloying after a while. Also, the glass you served it in was too tall. We recommend you try soaking the biscoff in coffee, the way you would for ladyfingers in a traditional tiramisu. That’s an unfortunate way to start this review, as actually we really liked eating here. The pizza was extremely good. Thin, crispy base. Cheesy but not too much. All the flavours worked really well together. And the rocket was carefully distributed and of an appropriate amount. We’d eat that again any day of the week. We were excited to see the dessert arancini, which was a first for us. The balls contained rice, like a fried rice pudding, with plenty of cinnamon, tonnes of blueberries, the right amount of white chocolate, the whole thing was top tier. The cauliflower was very controversial. The Fee-Rex found it bland, didn’t appreciate the cherry tomatoes, and was looking around on the table like is there some salt here I can apply. Business Andy thought it was marvellous. He could really taste the parmesan and thought the cherry tomatoes were a perfect accompaniment. We could at least both agree that the crispy roast bits on the edges were very pleasant.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ayhan’s Turkish Cafe</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/07/19/Ayhan-s-Turkish-Cafe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ayhan’s Turkish Cafe" /><published>2024-07-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/07/19/Ayhan%E2%80%99s-Turkish-Cafe</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/07/19/Ayhan-s-Turkish-Cafe/"><![CDATA[<p>Spinach and feta gozleme<br />
Lamb pide</p>

<p>Years ago, The Fee-Rex used to live in Perth where she discovered gozleme. It made up of a filling, often spinach and feta, sandwiched in a bready dough and cut into pieces. And it’s bloody delicious. Two years ago, we went to Perth and on our first night excitedly went searching for gozleme. What we got was a soggy disaster, an abomination not worthy of the name gozleme. And it was an awful introduction for Business Andy, who had never had the dish before and was very disappointed after literally years worth of hype.</p>

<p>Fast forward to today, it is again our first night on a Perth holiday, and we are again chasing the gozleme dragon. But this time, we slayed it. Hot, fresh, squishy but not too squishy and absolutely zero sogginess. The pide dough was yum, but the filling was a bit light on flavour and tasted too much like just lamb mince.</p>

<p>Shout out to Ayhan and his service. He was friendly, served us on proper plates/wooden boards with proper cutlery (not a given, the soggy gozleme place served us in takeaway boxes), gave us a bowl of accompanying sauce AND three after-dinner mentos. We appreciate the details.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spinach and feta gozleme Lamb pide Years ago, The Fee-Rex used to live in Perth where she discovered gozleme. It made up of a filling, often spinach and feta, sandwiched in a bready dough and cut into pieces. And it’s bloody delicious. Two years ago, we went to Perth and on our first night excitedly went searching for gozleme. What we got was a soggy disaster, an abomination not worthy of the name gozleme. And it was an awful introduction for Business Andy, who had never had the dish before and was very disappointed after literally years worth of hype. Fast forward to today, it is again our first night on a Perth holiday, and we are again chasing the gozleme dragon. But this time, we slayed it. Hot, fresh, squishy but not too squishy and absolutely zero sogginess. The pide dough was yum, but the filling was a bit light on flavour and tasted too much like just lamb mince. Shout out to Ayhan and his service. He was friendly, served us on proper plates/wooden boards with proper cutlery (not a given, the soggy gozleme place served us in takeaway boxes), gave us a bowl of accompanying sauce AND three after-dinner mentos. We appreciate the details.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Autobahn Cafe</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/03/20/Autobahn-Cafe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Autobahn Cafe" /><published>2024-03-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-03-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/03/20/Autobahn-Cafe</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/03/20/Autobahn-Cafe/"><![CDATA[<p>Beef nachos<br />
Lamb burger with chips<br />
Banana smoothie</p>

<p>It’s a bad sign if your establishment reminds us of Burger King. Both eateries were happy to spend big bucks on making the air conditioning freezing cold if it meant that punters would be in and out as fast as they could. And neither establishment had spared a dime to make the food any good.</p>

<p>The nachos were dreadful. The chips were extremely bland, thin and weak and almost all already broken when they arrived. The mince was flavoured, but not in a tasty way. Thank god there was enough sour cream, which is not a given in our experience.</p>

<p>The burger, proudly touted as gourmet, was anything but. Cheap greasy lamb patty, bog standard bun, and not a lot of care put into the cooking e.g. underdone floppy onion. The chips were hot and fresh with plenty of them, but where was the salt? They had provided salt on the table, although the shaker was 60% rice. But who wants to eat an unsalted chip? They also came with no aioli or sauce, although we were able to scavenge a bottle from the counter.</p>

<p>The smoothie was the best of the bunch, but a bit yoghurty and the presence of real banana was questionable. Also, this meal was bloody expensive for what it was. The sad fact is that the Autobahn has been around for many years, The Fee-Rex remembers coming here 25 years ago, and as long as people with low standards are driving in and out of Auckland, it will be here for many years to come.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beef nachos Lamb burger with chips Banana smoothie It’s a bad sign if your establishment reminds us of Burger King. Both eateries were happy to spend big bucks on making the air conditioning freezing cold if it meant that punters would be in and out as fast as they could. And neither establishment had spared a dime to make the food any good. The nachos were dreadful. The chips were extremely bland, thin and weak and almost all already broken when they arrived. The mince was flavoured, but not in a tasty way. Thank god there was enough sour cream, which is not a given in our experience. The burger, proudly touted as gourmet, was anything but. Cheap greasy lamb patty, bog standard bun, and not a lot of care put into the cooking e.g. underdone floppy onion. The chips were hot and fresh with plenty of them, but where was the salt? They had provided salt on the table, although the shaker was 60% rice. But who wants to eat an unsalted chip? They also came with no aioli or sauce, although we were able to scavenge a bottle from the counter. The smoothie was the best of the bunch, but a bit yoghurty and the presence of real banana was questionable. Also, this meal was bloody expensive for what it was. The sad fact is that the Autobahn has been around for many years, The Fee-Rex remembers coming here 25 years ago, and as long as people with low standards are driving in and out of Auckland, it will be here for many years to come.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stratosfare Restaurant &amp;amp; Bar</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/02/22/Stratosfare-Restaurant-&-Bar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stratosfare Restaurant &amp;amp; Bar" /><published>2024-02-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/02/22/Stratosfare-Restaurant-&amp;-Bar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/02/22/Stratosfare-Restaurant-&amp;-Bar/"><![CDATA[<p>Buffet</p>

<p>A buffet is such a rare dining experience for us that when we realise we’re heading into a buffet, for a second we get a bit excited. Then the irrefutable truth of the buffet dawns on us and we remember that, while good buffets do exist, they are extremely rare.</p>

<p>Stratosfare thinks quite highly of itself, but doesn’t have the chops (or other meats) to back it up. We will say they are correct about the view, it’s pretty nice. And we appreciated the bustling hive of activity up on the hill, between the mountain bike competition, the gondolas, the luge, the freshly sheared alpacas, there was plenty to see.</p>

<p>Stratosfare is a bar, as well as a restaurant, and they have a good looking cocktail menu. Unfortunately, the cocktails themselves were downright awful. We got a salted caramel espresso martini and a black forest mudslide. Yum yum, right? Wrong. After taking an extremely long time to arrive, the black forest had a nasty liquer taste while the martini was watery and not sweet, and didn’t have that delicious coffee flavour either. We often scarf down cocktails at lightning speed; these two were both left at the end of the meal and it was hard going to finish them.</p>

<p>Nothing from the buffet was really worth eating. The raspberry jelly was alright. The brownie was alright, but we don’t believe any of the slices, or the hard bready little donuts, were made on site. The roast potatoes were acceptable but lacked crispness. The bread rolls were squished and firm. The 24-hour slow roast beef with homemade gravy was a great disappointment. The guy was carving it right there, he could work around the gristle if he wanted. But he didn’t want to, and the Fee-Rex literally had to spit a piece out when she found out it was 80% hyper-chewy gristle. The gravy was foul. It had a very strong flavour like somebody had put in a whole tub of Marmite. Hell, maybe even a whole tub of Vegemite.</p>

<p>The desserts were the best of a bad bunch. The pavlova was okay with a nice mix of fruit on top. They offered six different ice cream flavours, which we appreciated, but it was all very airy, non-creamy, the cheapest of the cheap. The mousse had a bitter cocoa flavour. We definitely regretted the amount of dessert we took, so if you are going to come to Stratosfare (which you shouldn’t), approach with caution.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Buffet A buffet is such a rare dining experience for us that when we realise we’re heading into a buffet, for a second we get a bit excited. Then the irrefutable truth of the buffet dawns on us and we remember that, while good buffets do exist, they are extremely rare. Stratosfare thinks quite highly of itself, but doesn’t have the chops (or other meats) to back it up. We will say they are correct about the view, it’s pretty nice. And we appreciated the bustling hive of activity up on the hill, between the mountain bike competition, the gondolas, the luge, the freshly sheared alpacas, there was plenty to see. Stratosfare is a bar, as well as a restaurant, and they have a good looking cocktail menu. Unfortunately, the cocktails themselves were downright awful. We got a salted caramel espresso martini and a black forest mudslide. Yum yum, right? Wrong. After taking an extremely long time to arrive, the black forest had a nasty liquer taste while the martini was watery and not sweet, and didn’t have that delicious coffee flavour either. We often scarf down cocktails at lightning speed; these two were both left at the end of the meal and it was hard going to finish them. Nothing from the buffet was really worth eating. The raspberry jelly was alright. The brownie was alright, but we don’t believe any of the slices, or the hard bready little donuts, were made on site. The roast potatoes were acceptable but lacked crispness. The bread rolls were squished and firm. The 24-hour slow roast beef with homemade gravy was a great disappointment. The guy was carving it right there, he could work around the gristle if he wanted. But he didn’t want to, and the Fee-Rex literally had to spit a piece out when she found out it was 80% hyper-chewy gristle. The gravy was foul. It had a very strong flavour like somebody had put in a whole tub of Marmite. Hell, maybe even a whole tub of Vegemite. The desserts were the best of a bad bunch. The pavlova was okay with a nice mix of fruit on top. They offered six different ice cream flavours, which we appreciated, but it was all very airy, non-creamy, the cheapest of the cheap. The mousse had a bitter cocoa flavour. We definitely regretted the amount of dessert we took, so if you are going to come to Stratosfare (which you shouldn’t), approach with caution.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Madly Indian</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2023/12/08/Madly-Indian/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Madly Indian" /><published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2023/12/08/Madly-Indian</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2023/12/08/Madly-Indian/"><![CDATA[<p>Lamb do pyaza<br />
Paneer chettinaud<br />
Butter naan<br />
Cheese naan</p>

<p>While it can be hard to stand out when you’re an Indian restaurant, doing the basics right can take you a long way. So while they didn’t quite take us to the moon and back, truly Madly deeply Indian certainly didn’t crash and burn.</p>

<p>The best thing was probably the chettinaud sauce, and the worst was  the cheese naan, in which none of the promised cheddar appeared. That was Edam at best. We don’t know why Business Andy keeps ordering cheese naans, they just end up breaking his heart every time.  Special shout out to Madly Indian’s rice, they’d added some extra spices which really elevated it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lamb do pyaza Paneer chettinaud Butter naan Cheese naan While it can be hard to stand out when you’re an Indian restaurant, doing the basics right can take you a long way. So while they didn’t quite take us to the moon and back, truly Madly deeply Indian certainly didn’t crash and burn. The best thing was probably the chettinaud sauce, and the worst was the cheese naan, in which none of the promised cheddar appeared. That was Edam at best. We don’t know why Business Andy keeps ordering cheese naans, they just end up breaking his heart every time. Special shout out to Madly Indian’s rice, they’d added some extra spices which really elevated it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Zane Grey’s Restaurant &amp;amp; Bar</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2023/12/08/Zane-Grey's-Restaurant-&-Bar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zane Grey’s Restaurant &amp;amp; Bar" /><published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-12-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2023/12/08/Zane-Grey&apos;s-Restaurant-&amp;-Bar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2023/12/08/Zane-Grey&apos;s-Restaurant-&amp;-Bar/"><![CDATA[<p>Fish chips and salad<br />
Cheese burger with chips</p>

<p>Screw you Zane. We’ve been to places like this before, tourist traps with a great location who then don’t need to try because they know people will come in thanks to the location, and with most just passing through return business is no concern.</p>

<p>Fair play, it is a beautiful spot with plenty of seating on a large deck jutting out into the water, the kind of place you can watch the birds and hope to see a dolphin.</p>

<p>That’s where the compliments end. Here are their food crimes in no particular order</p>
<ul>
  <li>Overpriced</li>
  <li>The worlds tiniest sliver of lemon to squeeze on the fish. You couldn’t even squeeze it, it just crumpled into dust, that’s how thin it was. It was less than enough lemon for a gin and tonic</li>
  <li>Menu said aioli then the chips came with tomato sauce instead. Stop it you lazy fucks.</li>
  <li>Totally gutless tartare sauce. It was so gutless it might have actually just been bland aioli, but it came with the fish we figured it was meant to be tartare.</li>
  <li>Bad chips. We had difficulty pinpointing what exactly made them bad, they were not cold or soggy or anything obvious, they just didn’t taste good and were a labour to get through</li>
  <li>Terrible distribution of bacon in the burger. It was literally all in one corner, meaning that Business Andy never even knew there was bacon in the burger at all as his half contained zero bacon.</li>
</ul>

<p>We won’t stand for it, Zane.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fish chips and salad Cheese burger with chips Screw you Zane. We’ve been to places like this before, tourist traps with a great location who then don’t need to try because they know people will come in thanks to the location, and with most just passing through return business is no concern. Fair play, it is a beautiful spot with plenty of seating on a large deck jutting out into the water, the kind of place you can watch the birds and hope to see a dolphin. That’s where the compliments end. Here are their food crimes in no particular order Overpriced The worlds tiniest sliver of lemon to squeeze on the fish. You couldn’t even squeeze it, it just crumpled into dust, that’s how thin it was. It was less than enough lemon for a gin and tonic Menu said aioli then the chips came with tomato sauce instead. Stop it you lazy fucks. Totally gutless tartare sauce. It was so gutless it might have actually just been bland aioli, but it came with the fish we figured it was meant to be tartare. Bad chips. We had difficulty pinpointing what exactly made them bad, they were not cold or soggy or anything obvious, they just didn’t taste good and were a labour to get through Terrible distribution of bacon in the burger. It was literally all in one corner, meaning that Business Andy never even knew there was bacon in the burger at all as his half contained zero bacon. We won’t stand for it, Zane.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/default-social-image.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>