<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2025-04-29T07:14:29+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/feed.xml</id><title type="html">BAATFR</title><subtitle>Restaurant reviews</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kaimak</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/04/24/Kaimak/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kaimak" /><published>2025-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/04/24/Kaimak</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/04/24/Kaimak/"><![CDATA[<p>Salami pide<br />
Halloumi iskender</p>

<p>It’s a tough decision for places trying to do well in both takeaway and dine-in; door open or door closed? On one hand, door open helps traffic flow and encourages customers for the takeaway trade, as well as discouraging loitering dine-in clientele (AKA the Burger King technique). On the other hand, it’s pretty bloody cold in autumn for your dine in customers. We ate in our puffer jackets.</p>

<p>Luckily, the food was very good. The pide was flavourful with good sized chunks of salami, it wasn’t greasy like some pide can be, and the ends weren’t just useless nubbins of doughy bread, the topping went all the way to the end. It also came with two fantastic accompaniments - yellow chillis and pickled cabbage. We were skeptical when we saw these. The waiter warned us the chillis were hot, and he was quite correct as the Fee-Rex learned when she tried to eat one straight up. However, when used as intended as a pairing to the pide it was a fantastic addition, as was the cabbage.</p>

<p>The halloumi iskender was also strong. There was plenty of everything and in good ratios. Generous with the hummus too, which is nice to see. Yes there could have been more halloumi, but that’s basically always the case.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Salami pide Halloumi iskender It’s a tough decision for places trying to do well in both takeaway and dine-in; door open or door closed? On one hand, door open helps traffic flow and encourages customers for the takeaway trade, as well as discouraging loitering dine-in clientele (AKA the Burger King technique). On the other hand, it’s pretty bloody cold in autumn for your dine in customers. We ate in our puffer jackets. Luckily, the food was very good. The pide was flavourful with good sized chunks of salami, it wasn’t greasy like some pide can be, and the ends weren’t just useless nubbins of doughy bread, the topping went all the way to the end. It also came with two fantastic accompaniments - yellow chillis and pickled cabbage. We were skeptical when we saw these. The waiter warned us the chillis were hot, and he was quite correct as the Fee-Rex learned when she tried to eat one straight up. However, when used as intended as a pairing to the pide it was a fantastic addition, as was the cabbage. The halloumi iskender was also strong. There was plenty of everything and in good ratios. Generous with the hummus too, which is nice to see. Yes there could have been more halloumi, but that’s basically always the case.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clearview Estate</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/02/20/Clearview-Estate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clearview Estate" /><published>2025-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/02/20/Clearview-Estate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/02/20/Clearview-Estate/"><![CDATA[<p>Bread with butter and hummus<br />
Profiteroles with pumpkin hummus, feta, cucumber<br />
Eye fillet with confit potato, brocollini, carrot, turnip and jus<br />
Mushroom arancini in tomato sauce<br />
Baileys creme brûlée<br />
Affogato</p>

<p>On a warm, still Hawkes Bay day, Clearview is a bloody nice place to eat. As part of a large group we got a table under cover nestled amongst the vines with a gentle breeze coming through, pure perfection. Also as part of a large group, we were happy to drink and be merry with our own company. Which is a lucky thing, as we were in for a wait. To their credit, the waiter did let us know they were extremely busy and bring out some complimentary bread. Regardless, the wait was substantial. What was worse than the wait, however, was the dripping nature with which food came out. There shouldn’t be a fifteen minute gap between the first and last meal coming out, that’s just poor kitchen management.</p>

<p>Much of the food was worth the weight. We can wholeheartedly recommend the steak, arancini and particularly the profiteroles which were inventive and exciting. Unfortunately the bread and the dessert let the meal down a bit. The bread was perfectly fine, but wasn’t anything to write home about, as was the adffogato. The brûlée was the worst of the lot, with way too much baileys in it which frankly ruined the flavour.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bread with butter and hummus Profiteroles with pumpkin hummus, feta, cucumber Eye fillet with confit potato, brocollini, carrot, turnip and jus Mushroom arancini in tomato sauce Baileys creme brûlée Affogato On a warm, still Hawkes Bay day, Clearview is a bloody nice place to eat. As part of a large group we got a table under cover nestled amongst the vines with a gentle breeze coming through, pure perfection. Also as part of a large group, we were happy to drink and be merry with our own company. Which is a lucky thing, as we were in for a wait. To their credit, the waiter did let us know they were extremely busy and bring out some complimentary bread. Regardless, the wait was substantial. What was worse than the wait, however, was the dripping nature with which food came out. There shouldn’t be a fifteen minute gap between the first and last meal coming out, that’s just poor kitchen management. Much of the food was worth the weight. We can wholeheartedly recommend the steak, arancini and particularly the profiteroles which were inventive and exciting. Unfortunately the bread and the dessert let the meal down a bit. The bread was perfectly fine, but wasn’t anything to write home about, as was the adffogato. The brûlée was the worst of the lot, with way too much baileys in it which frankly ruined the flavour.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Crack Chicken</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/02/07/Crack-Chicken/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crack Chicken" /><published>2025-02-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-02-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/02/07/Crack-Chicken</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2025/02/07/Crack-Chicken/"><![CDATA[<p>Classic fried chicken bowl<br />
Single beef burger<br />
Waffle fries with gochujang mayo</p>

<p>Billed as an innovative, mouthwatering cross between Nashville-style and Korean-style fried chicken, the reality is that it’s just a middling fast food joint in an underground food court. While the chicken itself was actually quite good, everything else in the bowl was just a huge slog. And it was all made worse, or at least much harder to eat by the awful wooden fork.</p>

<p>The burger was okay overall, although the bun was far too dry, and the same for the patty. At least the sauces were pretty good.</p>

<p>The waffle fries were the complete opposite experience, good waffle fries, but awful sauce. It was supposed to be gochujang mayo, but that flavour was indiscernible, it may as well have just had a few drops of tabasco sauce in it for all we could taste.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Classic fried chicken bowl Single beef burger Waffle fries with gochujang mayo Billed as an innovative, mouthwatering cross between Nashville-style and Korean-style fried chicken, the reality is that it’s just a middling fast food joint in an underground food court. While the chicken itself was actually quite good, everything else in the bowl was just a huge slog. And it was all made worse, or at least much harder to eat by the awful wooden fork. The burger was okay overall, although the bun was far too dry, and the same for the patty. At least the sauces were pretty good. The waffle fries were the complete opposite experience, good waffle fries, but awful sauce. It was supposed to be gochujang mayo, but that flavour was indiscernible, it may as well have just had a few drops of tabasco sauce in it for all we could taste.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A1 Takeaways Hong Kong Style BBQ</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A1 Takeaways Hong Kong Style BBQ" /><published>2024-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/08/A1-Takeaways-Hong-Kong-Style-BBQ/"><![CDATA[<p>Shredded duck with plum sauce on rice<br />
Tofu with vegetables and spicy sauce on rice</p>

<p>A1 Takeaways, despite the name, does do dine-in. It’s only 4 tables, but you’ll probably be fine without a reservation. We were impressed that, compared to recent experiences, A1 asked us if we were dining in and, when we said yes, served us on a plate rather than in a takeaway container. Was the plate paper and the cutlery a wooden fork? Sure. But some effort was made. We also enjoyed when a squad of four lads came in later who were clearly friendly with the owner. They were having a good yarn and organising dates for something. It gave a sense that A1 is a real part of the community. Points for super speedy service, and for value for money too. (especially the tofu - $13.50 for a full sized meal!)</p>

<p>We regret that we’re unable to gush so emphatically about the food itself. The duck was of pretty good quality, nice skin, but came chopped rather than shredded as advertised. The plum sauce was extremely sweet, pale, and not recognisable as plum. The tofu had an unpleasant fryer taste and the ‘spicy’ sauce was more sweet than spicy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shredded duck with plum sauce on rice Tofu with vegetables and spicy sauce on rice A1 Takeaways, despite the name, does do dine-in. It’s only 4 tables, but you’ll probably be fine without a reservation. We were impressed that, compared to recent experiences, A1 asked us if we were dining in and, when we said yes, served us on a plate rather than in a takeaway container. Was the plate paper and the cutlery a wooden fork? Sure. But some effort was made. We also enjoyed when a squad of four lads came in later who were clearly friendly with the owner. They were having a good yarn and organising dates for something. It gave a sense that A1 is a real part of the community. Points for super speedy service, and for value for money too. (especially the tofu - $13.50 for a full sized meal!) We regret that we’re unable to gush so emphatically about the food itself. The duck was of pretty good quality, nice skin, but came chopped rather than shredded as advertised. The plum sauce was extremely sweet, pale, and not recognisable as plum. The tofu had an unpleasant fryer taste and the ‘spicy’ sauce was more sweet than spicy.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rusty Bros</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rusty Bros" /><published>2024-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/03/The-Rusty-Bros/"><![CDATA[<p>Strawberry milkshake<br />
Jackfruit sliders<br />
Polenta chips<br />
Garlic bread</p>

<p>Let us tell you what we don’t appreciate. Lies. Restaurants who claim a quality or nature of ingredients that makes them sound fancy, tricks you into ordering, then doesn’t deliver. How would you like to try a strawberry milkshake made with strawberry ganache? Sounds pretty good doesn’t it? So you could colour us disappointed when we saw with our own eyes the waiter pumping some kind of bottled syrup into our milkshake. Also, lies on lies, where was the coleslaw and aioli in the sliders? Hanging out with the strawberry ganache in imaginary-land probably!</p>

<p>The highlight of the meal was the garlic bread. It was hot and fresh with plenty of garlic butter and a lovely roasty garlic flavour. But enough of the compliments, let’s talk about the polenta chips. Perhaps they had been fried too long, perhaps they were just cheap old frozen polenta chips, but either way they were dry as a fortnight of Sundays and while you could see the rosemary, you certainly couldn’t taste it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Strawberry milkshake Jackfruit sliders Polenta chips Garlic bread Let us tell you what we don’t appreciate. Lies. Restaurants who claim a quality or nature of ingredients that makes them sound fancy, tricks you into ordering, then doesn’t deliver. How would you like to try a strawberry milkshake made with strawberry ganache? Sounds pretty good doesn’t it? So you could colour us disappointed when we saw with our own eyes the waiter pumping some kind of bottled syrup into our milkshake. Also, lies on lies, where was the coleslaw and aioli in the sliders? Hanging out with the strawberry ganache in imaginary-land probably! The highlight of the meal was the garlic bread. It was hot and fresh with plenty of garlic butter and a lovely roasty garlic flavour. But enough of the compliments, let’s talk about the polenta chips. Perhaps they had been fried too long, perhaps they were just cheap old frozen polenta chips, but either way they were dry as a fortnight of Sundays and while you could see the rosemary, you certainly couldn’t taste it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Urban Gusto</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Urban Gusto" /><published>2024-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/11/02/Urban-Gusto/"><![CDATA[<p>Pear, gongonzola, rocket and pine nut pizza<br />
Roasted cauliflower with parmesan and cherry tomatoes<br />
Biscoff tiramisu<br />
White chocolate blueberry arancini</p>

<p>Something very unusual happened at Urban Gusto this evening. We were asked for genuine feedback. We’re not talking about the perfunctory “how was your meal” either. When dropping off the tiramisu, the waiter said “we’ve had this on the specials menu for a couple of weeks, would love your feedback.” We subsequently didn’t see that waiter again, but hopefully he gets to read this review. So here goes - the flavours were yummy, we liked the crumbled up biscoff on the top, but that was not a tiramisu. It had no coffee. Also it was very sweet, especially with the caramel in the bottom so it became cloying after a while. Also, the glass you served it in was too tall. We recommend you try soaking the biscoff in coffee, the way you would for ladyfingers in a traditional tiramisu.</p>

<p>That’s an unfortunate way to start this review, as actually we really liked eating here. The pizza was extremely good. Thin, crispy base. Cheesy but not too much. All the flavours worked really well together. And the rocket was carefully distributed and of an appropriate amount. We’d eat that again any day of the week. We were excited to see the dessert arancini, which was a first for us. The balls contained rice, like a fried rice pudding, with plenty of cinnamon, tonnes of blueberries, the right amount of white chocolate, the whole thing was top tier.</p>

<p>The cauliflower was very controversial. The Fee-Rex found it bland, didn’t appreciate the cherry tomatoes, and was looking around on the table like is there some salt here I can apply. Business Andy thought it was marvellous. He could really taste the parmesan and thought the cherry tomatoes were a perfect accompaniment. We could at least both agree that the crispy roast bits on the edges were very pleasant.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pear, gongonzola, rocket and pine nut pizza Roasted cauliflower with parmesan and cherry tomatoes Biscoff tiramisu White chocolate blueberry arancini Something very unusual happened at Urban Gusto this evening. We were asked for genuine feedback. We’re not talking about the perfunctory “how was your meal” either. When dropping off the tiramisu, the waiter said “we’ve had this on the specials menu for a couple of weeks, would love your feedback.” We subsequently didn’t see that waiter again, but hopefully he gets to read this review. So here goes - the flavours were yummy, we liked the crumbled up biscoff on the top, but that was not a tiramisu. It had no coffee. Also it was very sweet, especially with the caramel in the bottom so it became cloying after a while. Also, the glass you served it in was too tall. We recommend you try soaking the biscoff in coffee, the way you would for ladyfingers in a traditional tiramisu. That’s an unfortunate way to start this review, as actually we really liked eating here. The pizza was extremely good. Thin, crispy base. Cheesy but not too much. All the flavours worked really well together. And the rocket was carefully distributed and of an appropriate amount. We’d eat that again any day of the week. We were excited to see the dessert arancini, which was a first for us. The balls contained rice, like a fried rice pudding, with plenty of cinnamon, tonnes of blueberries, the right amount of white chocolate, the whole thing was top tier. The cauliflower was very controversial. The Fee-Rex found it bland, didn’t appreciate the cherry tomatoes, and was looking around on the table like is there some salt here I can apply. Business Andy thought it was marvellous. He could really taste the parmesan and thought the cherry tomatoes were a perfect accompaniment. We could at least both agree that the crispy roast bits on the edges were very pleasant.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Suncourt Indian</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/26/Suncourt-Indian/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Suncourt Indian" /><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/26/Suncourt-Indian</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/26/Suncourt-Indian/"><![CDATA[<p>Shahi paneer<br />
Butter naan<br />
Cheese naan</p>

<p>Suncourt Indian isn’t part of a food court, but it has that vibe. There are bain-maries which is always concerning, however we were pleased to see that our food was made fresh. Why did they put a couple of bits of grated cheese on top of the curry? We’re not quite sure. The shahi paneer was way too sweet, and the paneer was cardboardy, but we appreciated the generous serving of rice and the friendly service.</p>

<p>The cheese naan was hot and fresh with a pleasant texture. As per usual, Business Andy was disappointed yet again by the presence of mozzarella, nobody knows why he continues to order cheese naans. The butter naan was a bit dry in some places and thick in others, it was only okay overall.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shahi paneer Butter naan Cheese naan Suncourt Indian isn’t part of a food court, but it has that vibe. There are bain-maries which is always concerning, however we were pleased to see that our food was made fresh. Why did they put a couple of bits of grated cheese on top of the curry? We’re not quite sure. The shahi paneer was way too sweet, and the paneer was cardboardy, but we appreciated the generous serving of rice and the friendly service. The cheese naan was hot and fresh with a pleasant texture. As per usual, Business Andy was disappointed yet again by the presence of mozzarella, nobody knows why he continues to order cheese naans. The butter naan was a bit dry in some places and thick in others, it was only okay overall.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tongariro Lodge</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/26/Tongariro-Lodge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tongariro Lodge" /><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/26/Tongariro-Lodge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/26/Tongariro-Lodge/"><![CDATA[<p>Flatbread with hummus and harissa seed oil<br />
Honey roasted carrots<br />
Cauliflower steak<br />
Fries with truffle aioli<br />
Halloumi, grapes and chorizo<br />
Fried chicken with wasabi mayo and sweet soy<br />
Burnt New York style cheesecake with parmesan and yuzu</p>

<p>What a glow up. It’s hard to believe that 3 years ago we slapped this place with a 2 after being served one of the worst fish dishes of all time (perhaps it’s a three-way tie with White Horse Inn and LA Bakery &amp; Coffee Lounge). Tonight, they have achieved our highest accolade, the coveted 4 rating.</p>

<p>While Tongariro Lodge is not a tapas restaurant, tonight our group of 4 chose to order a bunch of plates and share them round. There wasn’t a dud in the bunch. The halloumi, grapes and chorizo wasn’t particularly exciting, but it was tasty. Perhaps the chicken itself could have had a bit more excitement in texture or flavour, but it was well compensated by two delicious sauces.</p>

<p>Then we come to the stronger dishes. The flatbread came with a great hummus and was super well laminated and piping hot. The honey roasted carrots had a lovely honey flavour and were cooked just right. But two dishes stood above the rest. The cauliflower steak had this gorgeous flavour, the kind that makes you go ‘why can’t I make cauliflower like this at home, what have they done here?’ The cheesecake was very strange, with parmesan for goodness sake, but it totally worked. The top was burnt like a brulee and it came with brulee’d fruit too, everything worked together. We’ve never had a cheesecake like this before, big points for innovation. Welcome to the upper echelon, Tongariro Lodge.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flatbread with hummus and harissa seed oil Honey roasted carrots Cauliflower steak Fries with truffle aioli Halloumi, grapes and chorizo Fried chicken with wasabi mayo and sweet soy Burnt New York style cheesecake with parmesan and yuzu What a glow up. It’s hard to believe that 3 years ago we slapped this place with a 2 after being served one of the worst fish dishes of all time (perhaps it’s a three-way tie with White Horse Inn and LA Bakery &amp; Coffee Lounge). Tonight, they have achieved our highest accolade, the coveted 4 rating. While Tongariro Lodge is not a tapas restaurant, tonight our group of 4 chose to order a bunch of plates and share them round. There wasn’t a dud in the bunch. The halloumi, grapes and chorizo wasn’t particularly exciting, but it was tasty. Perhaps the chicken itself could have had a bit more excitement in texture or flavour, but it was well compensated by two delicious sauces. Then we come to the stronger dishes. The flatbread came with a great hummus and was super well laminated and piping hot. The honey roasted carrots had a lovely honey flavour and were cooked just right. But two dishes stood above the rest. The cauliflower steak had this gorgeous flavour, the kind that makes you go ‘why can’t I make cauliflower like this at home, what have they done here?’ The cheesecake was very strange, with parmesan for goodness sake, but it totally worked. The top was burnt like a brulee and it came with brulee’d fruit too, everything worked together. We’ve never had a cheesecake like this before, big points for innovation. Welcome to the upper echelon, Tongariro Lodge.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Golden Crust Pizza</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/25/Golden-Crust-Pizza/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Golden Crust Pizza" /><published>2024-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/25/Golden-Crust-Pizza</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/10/25/Golden-Crust-Pizza/"><![CDATA[<p>Peri-peri paneer pizza<br />
Chicken tenders with chips and sweet chilli sauce<br />
Caramel thickshake</p>

<p>What is it to ‘dine-in’? Business Andy and the Fee-Rex only review dine-establishments. Golden Crust Pizza’s signage states dine-in. And there are some tables and chairs, with salt and pepper at the tables. Sounds like dine-in so far. There was no table service, you had to order at the counter, but that’s fine. Failure to provide water (except purchased bottled water) is unpleasant, but certainly not unprecedented, plenty of dingy cafe’s do the same thing. The stickiness of the table was a clue that other patrons had also chosen to dine-in.</p>

<p>When we ordered the server didn’t ask dine-in or takeaway, which is a red flag. To ensure they knew, we even went up after ordering to tell them we were intending to dine-in. They did not bring the order to the table, instead they yell your name and you have to go up and get it, the red flag waving was getting quite intense at this point. The order comes in takeaway packaging with no cutlery provided, a cascade of red flags with flashing lights. We’d describe Golden Crust more as dine-in tolerated than a dine-in restaurant. The South Asian news playing on the huge telly above our table showing images of dying elephants didn’t exactly stoke our appetite either.</p>

<p>What did get our juices flowing was the pizza. Yum. It was spicy, but not too spicy, with great paneer, a good balance of other ingredients and the peri-peri sauce was ample but not excessive. The chicken tenders were also a pleasant surprise. They were sizeable and actually pretty tender, crumbed and served with a kinda-thin sweet chilli sauce.</p>

<p>The chips were not good; way under-salted and only just cooked. The thickshake was also a real shame. If you’re advertising a thickshake, that shake had better be thick. I’m talking hard-to-get-up-the-straw thick. This shake had been made with softserve ice cream and had a foamy texture, definitely not thick, and the caramel flavour was uninspired.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Peri-peri paneer pizza Chicken tenders with chips and sweet chilli sauce Caramel thickshake What is it to ‘dine-in’? Business Andy and the Fee-Rex only review dine-establishments. Golden Crust Pizza’s signage states dine-in. And there are some tables and chairs, with salt and pepper at the tables. Sounds like dine-in so far. There was no table service, you had to order at the counter, but that’s fine. Failure to provide water (except purchased bottled water) is unpleasant, but certainly not unprecedented, plenty of dingy cafe’s do the same thing. The stickiness of the table was a clue that other patrons had also chosen to dine-in. When we ordered the server didn’t ask dine-in or takeaway, which is a red flag. To ensure they knew, we even went up after ordering to tell them we were intending to dine-in. They did not bring the order to the table, instead they yell your name and you have to go up and get it, the red flag waving was getting quite intense at this point. The order comes in takeaway packaging with no cutlery provided, a cascade of red flags with flashing lights. We’d describe Golden Crust more as dine-in tolerated than a dine-in restaurant. The South Asian news playing on the huge telly above our table showing images of dying elephants didn’t exactly stoke our appetite either. What did get our juices flowing was the pizza. Yum. It was spicy, but not too spicy, with great paneer, a good balance of other ingredients and the peri-peri sauce was ample but not excessive. The chicken tenders were also a pleasant surprise. They were sizeable and actually pretty tender, crumbed and served with a kinda-thin sweet chilli sauce. The chips were not good; way under-salted and only just cooked. The thickshake was also a real shame. If you’re advertising a thickshake, that shake had better be thick. I’m talking hard-to-get-up-the-straw thick. This shake had been made with softserve ice cream and had a foamy texture, definitely not thick, and the caramel flavour was uninspired.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mr Glen’s Taphouse &amp;amp; Tapas</title><link href="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/08/10/Mr-Glen's-Taphouse-&-Tapas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mr Glen’s Taphouse &amp;amp; Tapas" /><published>2024-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/08/10/Mr-Glen&apos;s-Taphouse-&amp;-Tapas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/reviews/2024/08/10/Mr-Glen&apos;s-Taphouse-&amp;-Tapas/"><![CDATA[<p>Pork belly tacos<br />
Tofu and mushroom bao buns</p>

<p>Don’t let the name fool you, Mr Glen’s is a taphouse but not a tapas bar. Their ‘tapas’ were things like chips, garlic bread, wings. By that definition, Lone Star is a tapas bar.</p>

<p>Mr Glen’s menu was large, and we appreciated the funny names (our pork belly tacos were officially called “Damn That’s Hot”, even though they were mild at most). But the food was only so-so. The pork belly had good flavour, and the tacos were generously filled, but the belly itself was too dry. Similarly, the bao buns were generously stuffed, but the buns themselves were too thick and the dish lacked flavour.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pork belly tacos Tofu and mushroom bao buns Don’t let the name fool you, Mr Glen’s is a taphouse but not a tapas bar. Their ‘tapas’ were things like chips, garlic bread, wings. By that definition, Lone Star is a tapas bar. Mr Glen’s menu was large, and we appreciated the funny names (our pork belly tacos were officially called “Damn That’s Hot”, even though they were mild at most). But the food was only so-so. The pork belly had good flavour, and the tacos were generously filled, but the belly itself was too dry. Similarly, the bao buns were generously stuffed, but the buns themselves were too thick and the dish lacked flavour.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.buisinessandyandthefeerex.co.nz/assets/logos/logo.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>